Absalom Bull papers
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Absalom Bull papers
1776 - 1881
1815 - 1857
2 boxes (36 folders, 544 items) (2.0 linear ft.)
Bull, Absalom, 1797-1866
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
See also Mss. C00-1, Erie County Clerk's Office records.
Aetna Insurance Company; Black Rock Glass Company (Buffalo, N.Y.); Colored Citizens Committee (Buffalo, N.Y.); Jubilee Water Works Company (Buffalo, N.Y.); Niagara Steam Boat Company; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); St. Paul's Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Trinity Church (Buffalo, N.Y.); Whig Party (N.Y.); Black Rock Harbor (N.Y.); Buffalo Harbor (N.Y.); Erie Canal (N.Y.); Steuben County (N.Y.). Sheriff; Bull, Howell; Bull, William H.; Davis, S. (Saul), active 1860-1879; Day, David F. (David Fisher), 1828 or9-1900; Forward, Oliver, 1780-1834; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Porter, Peter B. (Peter Buell), 1773-1844; certificates; correspondence; financial records; memoirs; military commissions; speeches (documents); Fourth of July; Judges New York (State) Buffalo; Lawyers New York (State) Buffalo; Public Schools New York (State) Buffalo; Transportation New York (State) Buffalo
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
Absalom Bull was born in 1797 in Hamptonburgh, Orange County, New York. He was the son of Cadwallader Bull and Submit Watkins, making Absalom the great-grandson of William Bull and Sarah Wells. Absalom married Maria Lindsey (1789-) on September 30, 1822 in Montgomery, N.Y. and they had three children: Hugh (1823-); Maria (1825-1888); and Cadwallader (1827-1863). In 1821 Absalom and Maria settled in Black Rock. From there Bull held many different positions in Black Rock. He was a lawyer, Erie County Supreme Judge, Secretary of the Black Rock Harbor Company, Justice of Peace, Insurance agent, Tax assessor for Black Rock, Secretary of the Friends of the “American System,” on the Republican Central Committee of Vigilance for Erie County, a NYS Whig for Buffalo, chair for the Buffalo and Black Rock Railroad Company, President of the Board of Trustees for Black Rock, Commissioner of schools in Buffalo, inspector of elections and a collector of tolls for the Erie Canal. Bull passed away on February 21, 1866 of Paralysis.
Collection primarily consists of correspondence, legal documents and other papers. The second series chiefly pertains to Peter B. Porter, whom Bull represented.
Collection is arranged into three series:
I. Family papers, 1776-1812.
II. Absalom Bull papers, 1815-1851, with Subseries A-I as follows:
A. Personal papers, 1815-1851.
B. Political activities, 1821-1851.
C. Water transportation, 1822-1851.
D. Jubilee Water Works Company, 1827-1844.
E. Aetna Insurance Company, 1829-1833.
F. Commissioner of Deeds, 1833-1839.
G. Black Rock Glass Company, 1834-1835.
H. Black Rock Board of Trustees Tax Assessor, 1835-1849.
I. Buffalo and Black Rock Railroad, 1835-1851.
III. Legal career papers, 1819-1881 with subseries A-C as follows:
A. Personal papers, 1819-1857.
B. Representing Peter B. Porter, 1822-1843.
C. Various clients, 1820-1881.
Chronological arrangement within.
- I. Family papers, 1776-1812
  - Folder 1: Family papers, 1776-1812
- II. Absalom Bull papers, 1815-1851
  - Subseries A: Personal papers, 1815-1851
    - Folder 2: Correspondence received, 1815-1828
    - Folder 3: Correspondence received, 1829-1851
    - Folder 4: Speeches and miscellaneous church papers, 1843-1844 and n.d.
    - Folder 5: Receipts and insurance policies, 1830-1845
  - Subseries B: Political activities, 1821-1851
    - Folder 6: Political activities, 1821-1851
  - Subseries C: Water transportation, 1822-1851
    - Folder 7: Correspondence, 1822-1851
    - Folder 8: Legal documents, 1825-1848
    - Folder 9: Waterloo steamer, 1845
    - Folder 10: Financial records, 1824-1827
  - Subseries D: Jubilee Water Works Company, 1827-1844
    - Folder 11: Jubilee Water Works Company, 1827-1844
  - Subseries E: Aetna Insurance Company, 1829-1833
    - Folder 12: Aetna Insurance Company, 1829-1833
  - Subseries F: Commissioner of Deeds, 1833-1839
    - Folder 13: Commissioner of Deeds, 1833-1839
  - Subseries G: Black Rock Glass Company, 1834-1835
    - Folder 14: Black Rock Glass Company, 1834-1835
  - Subseries H: Black Rock Board of Trustees Tax Assessor, 1835-1849
    - Folder 15: Tax assessor records, 1835-1849
    - Folder 16: Tax assessor financial ledger (unbound), 1824-1826
  - Subseries I: Buffalo and Black Rock Railroad, 1835-1851
    - Folder 17: Buffalo and Black Rock Railroad, 1835-1851
- III. Legal career papers, 1819-1881
  - Subseries A: Personal papers, 1819-1857
    - Folder 18: Personal papers, 1819-1835
    - Folder 19: Personal papers, 1837-1845
    - Folder 20: Personal papers, 1845-1857
    - Folder 21: Lawyer papers, 1819-1826
    - Folder 22: Lawyer papers, 1826-1846
    - Folder 23: Law firm documents, 1821-1827
    - Folder 24: Justice of the Peace papers, 1831-1837
    - Judgeship papers, 1842-1843
  - Subseries B: Representing Peter B. Porter, 1822-1843
    - Folder 1: Peter B. Porter legal papers, 1822-1836
    - Folder 2: Porter and Bull attorneys, 1822-1836
    - Folder 3: Peter B. Porter v. David Day, 1823
    - Folder 4: Peter B. Porter v. Oliver Forward, 1823
    - Folder 5: Peter B. Porter transportation papers, 1825-1844
    - Folder 6: Peter B. Porter engineering service, 1829-1838
    - Folder 7: Peter B. Porter political activities, 1831-1841
    - Folder 8: Peter B. Porter v. Saul Davis, 1842-1843
    - Folder 9: Peter B. Porter, Augustus Porter, Benjamin Barton, et al. land holdings, 1811-1840
  - Subseries C: Various clients, 1820-1881
    - Folder 10: William A. Bird papers, 1828-1842
    - Various clients, 1820-1881